Let's take a look at how to structure your file system.
You should organize your user files
into multiple HFS datasets.
This better enables you to manage space,
control contention, and manage backup and recovery situations.
That said, this is just one way of managing an environment,
not the only one, and depending on individual requirements
might not necessarily be the best way.
For example, once the US dataset per user
might be difficult to manage,
another approach might be to divide the data
by application or by department.
Regardless, in many cases, this is the way to go.
The slash U directory in the root file system
should be an empty directory mount point for an HFS
that contains just directories or mount points
for each of your users.
This HFS dataset will be mounted automatically
at OMVS initialization.
As you add users to your system,
create a new HFS for each one,
mount that HFS at the specific mount point set aside
for that user, and then change the ownership
of the mount point directory to the user's ID.
This can be done in the Rex Exec
to simplify the process of adding a new user.
The advantages of this organization are that user files
are stored in a separate ZOS dataset for each user,
and the root dataset can be kept read-only.
Auto-mount is an optional facility that comes with ZOS Unix.
It can be implemented if you want it.
It mounts user datasets and other datasets as directed.
Auto-mount only mounts datasets as they are referenced,
and these mounts are transparent to the user.
Both HFS and ZFS can be auto-mounted.
You can use a single auto-mount policy
to manage both HFS and ZFS file systems.
The auto-mount facility is a way to ensure
that a user's file system is mounted automatically
whenever they access a file in it.
The support group builds a file to identify the users,
their file systems, and its mount characteristics.
When the auto-mount facility is started,
it monitors file access.
When a user attempts to access one of their files,
auto-mount recognizes the need for a mount.
If there's no activity to a file system
for a divine period of time,
well, then auto-mount can also unmount the file system.
This avoids the need for a super user
to mount file systems upon request.
Let's look at another facility
for enhanced performance of programs that access files.
Memory mapped files enable multiple processes
to share file data without each doing its own reads
and writes.
This is a function from the XPG 4.2 standard.
The kernel stores the pages of data
from the file in a data space.
A child process inherits the same mapping
as defined by the parent using the mmmap function.
Another process will need to open the file to map
to the same data pages in the data space.
There are associated commands to ensure
that the physical data on the storage device
is updated as necessary.
Now, this diagram provides a logical view
of the file system structure
and an overview of its interfaces.
A ZOS Unix user has multiple interfaces
to the hierarchical file system.
The POSIX interfaces are the C program functions
and the shell commands.
And there's the ZOS interfaces through the TSCoE commands
and from high level languages,
which can use ZOS callable services
to access the hierarchical files.
The hierarchical file system is divided
into a logical file system as LFS
and a physical file system PFS.
LFS presents a single interface to the file system.
LFS receives the access request from a user
and maps the request to the appropriate PFS.
The LFS assigns a descriptor to the request
from the file descriptor table.
PFS performs the actual work in the file system.
There are multiple PFSs in the file system.
HFS files support files on DASD.
PIPES support interprocess communication.
Character special files support terminal communication
and socket file systems support program
to program communications.
Next up, we're talking backup and recovery.